[MUSIC]
[音楽]
So let's start with describing this task in a little bit more detail.
では、このタスクについて、少し詳細に 文章化することから始めましょう。
Okay, so let's say we're sitting here, reading an article.
はい、私たちはここに座って、 記事を読んでいます。
Here we are, reading our article.
ここで、私たちは、
And actually it's Carlos who's reading this article,
実際には、この記事を 読んでいるのはCarlosですね。
because this is an article about soccer.
この記事はサッカーについての ものだからです。
Or as he would call it football if he was wearing his Argentina jersey
アルゼンチン代表のジャージを着ていたのなら 「フットボール」と呼ぶかもしれません。
or footsie ball if he was wearing his Brazil jersey and
ブラジル代表のジャージを着ていたなら 「フットシー」と呼ぶかもね。
clearly, I'm not pronouncing either of those words correctly.
明らかに、私はこれらの単語を どちらも正確に発音していません。
Carlos can correct me later.
Carlosが後で修正してくれるといいな。
But the point is that he likes this article and what we'd like
ただ、要は、彼はこの記事が 好きだということで、
to do is retrieve another article that he might be interested in reading.
私たちは彼が興味を持ちそうな 他の記事を取得したいと思っています。
But a question is how do we do this?
しかし、どうやればいいでしょう？
There are lots and lots of articles out there and I can't expect him to go and
巷にはたくさんの記事があります。 私は彼にそれぞれの記事を読んで、
read each of them and say yes, he's interested or no, he's not.
興味があるかないかを 言ってもらうことは期待できません。
So we like to think of a way to automatically retrieve a document that
このため、自動的に彼が興味を持ちそうな
might be of interest to him.
記事を取得する方法を 考える必要があります。
By questions here are first, how to we measure similarity between articles?
まず最初の疑問です。 どうやって記事の類似性を測定しますか？
We need to have that in order to say that this article is similar to the one he's
この記事が、今、彼が読んでいる 記事と似ているので、
reading now and might also be of interest to him.
彼も興味を持つかもしれない ということを言うための測定方法が必要です。
Or that, here's a large set of articles that are very different and
別の例では、ここに大量の記事が あるが、違いすぎて、
probably are not of interest to him.
おそらく彼は興味を示さないだろう ということを言うための測定方法が必要です。
And then the second question is, how are we gonna search over the articles that
それから2つ目の疑問です。 巷にある記事をくまなく検索して、
exist out there and retrieve the next article to recommend.
お薦めする次の記事を どうやって取得しますか？
[MUSIC]
[音楽]